<tool id="calculate_energy_1" name="Compute energy profile" version="0.1.0">
	<description>Compute energy profile</description>

  <command interpreter="bash">
		calculate_energy_wrapper.sh $output_galaxy $input_sequence $input_config
	</command>
	
  <inputs>
  	<param format="fasta" name="input_sequence" type="data" label="Input FASTA sequence file"/>
  	<param format="in" name="input_config" type="data" label="Open config file"/>
  </inputs>

	<outputs>
		<data format="bed" name="output_galaxy"/>
	</outputs>
	
	<test>
		<param name="input_sequence" value="buchnera_short.fasta"/>
		<param name="input_config" value="crp.in"/>
		<output name="output_galaxy" file="buchnera_short_crp.bed"/>
	</test>

	<help>
**What it does**

The program calculates the DNA deformation energy associated to the binding of a protein, along an input sequence. In the typical case, the protein binds 10-20 basepairs, and the energy profile is computed along a genomic sequence. 

The main program takes the sequence of interest (in the FASTA format) and a configuration file describing the protein-DNA complex model with a few computation parameters. The latter file can be generated in Galaxy with a subprogram or created by hand. 
IMPORTANT: the model is built from one or several high-resolution structures of the DNA-protein complex of interest: before any calculation can be carried out, these structures must first be incorporated into the program database with the dedicated subprogram (add_structure). This step must done only once for each structure. 

The calculation is based on the hypothesis that the protein imposes DNA's shape at the nanometer-scale. The bending energy is then calculated from the deformed configuration, using the sequence-dependent structure/elastic parameters for the internal base-pair or the base-pair step deformations. For proteins where several alternate structures are available (typically obtained with different DNA sequences), these can be combined in the calculation: for a given sequence, DNA then "chooses" the weight of each  conformation from the different Boltzmann weights. 

Computational requirements: the computation time and memory load are proportional to the analyzed sequence length and number of protein-bound nucleotides. For a single protein-DNA complex analyzed, the computation typically takes ~ 200 sec and lower 1Gb RAM for a 10 Mb sequence.


-----


**Dataset formats**

Computes an energy profile along a sequence
Usage:
- sequence_file: FASTA format
- conf_file: description of the calculation parameters: each line is made of a keyword and a value, separated by ":". See software help for complete list of keywords. The file can be generated in a Galaxy subprogram. 


-----


**Output format**

Bedgraph file with 5 columns:

1. Name of the sequence(s) (better use short names to reduce file size)
2. Position of the protein-bound reference nucleotide
3. Position of the protein-bound reference nucleotide
4. Deformation energy (in a.u. or pseudo k_B T)

Additional columns:

1. Starting nucleotide of the bound protein
2. Ending nucleotide of the bound protein
	</help>

</tool>
